<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/OralHistory/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/OralHistory/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-27T17:12:19+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/</id><title type="html">北大附中口述史</title><subtitle>在这里，读懂北大附中</subtitle><entry><title type="html">我的积木人生（胖叔叔）</title><link href="/OralHistory/my-building-block-life" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="我的积木人生（胖叔叔）" /><published>2021-03-26T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-03-26T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/my-building-block-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/my-building-block-life">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“我喜欢搭积木，那是我的兴趣。但逐渐地，我的兴趣变成了我的追求，我的梦想。最终，它变成了我的生活，我的工作，我的人生。”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;胖叔叔是我的姨父。具体地说，是我的老姨夫。他体态臃肿，小时候我们这辈的小孩子不知从何时开始就一直叫他“胖叔叔”，可能他从那时起就开始搭建自己的脂肪结构了吧。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;谈到“搭建”，胖叔叔是家里唯一一个在行的，身处建筑行业的他，在西北有个项目，常常出差到外地。而我也从未真正地了解过他。但经过这次与他面对面聊天的经历，同就读过北大附中的我挖掘出了他深藏已久的生命故事。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;采访人：王孟喆，北大附中2021届学生&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;口述人：胖叔叔，90级北大附中校友，毕业后进入清华大学，如今从事建筑行业的工作&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;一块积木的诞生&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;一块积木的诞生&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;从小我就爱玩一些小的游戏，我们当时的条件来说，只有各种简单的小积木，还没有现在那么好的积木，包括现在的乐高积木，我们没有那么复杂的东西。当时也就只有一些简单的三角形、圆形、正方形、菱形等等各种简易积木，然后再加上一些木棍，或者是冰棍等等这些东西，或者是编草，发挥自己的想象力，做一些小手工的物品，或者是搭一些很简单的积木。那个时候就完全靠自己的想象力，没有现成的模板，也没有示范性的成品可以参考和借鉴，一切都是靠自己的发挥。所以从那时候我的长辈，我的父母就说了，觉得我那时候搭个什么东西，比如搭个教堂知道是尖顶的，搭一个什么场馆或者运动场，会搭成圆形的环型的，他们也觉得搭得很像。所以在他们鼓励之下，在我的想象之下，我觉得我对建筑越来越感兴趣。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;一块积木的路途&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;一块积木的路途&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我的化学老师李老师和我的爸爸曾经在同一个学校当过老师，所以我们两个家庭也走得非常近，相当于是个邻居和同事的关系。李老师家里头的孩子也和我一样大，她家是两个孩子，都是女儿，是双胞胎。这俩女儿跟我当时在附中时候是同学。而当时李老师教化学，李老师对上课的要求非常严厉，非常严谨，然后对学生也非常负责。但是那时候对我来说，由于上了附中以后生活习惯和学习习惯的改变，逐渐地产生了一些变化，尤其是心理和性格上产生了变化，也产生一些逆反的心理。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;当时老师对我是格外地关注，格外严厉和格外地要求严苛。所以我记忆里头，说句最简单的话就是关爱加严厉，使你不由自主地会产生害怕的心理。举个例子，从小我也经常去老师家，老师家的两个女儿也经常来我们家，相互之间来往，包括互相在对方家里吃饭，都是一起长大的。所以到后来上了附中以后，由于我这些坏习惯的影响，逐渐我发现去老师家吃饭，变成了一种负担和害怕。你知道为什么吗？假如哪一天，我要是上课表现好了，他们两个女儿中间的一个会告诉我，说我妈妈说你今天表现得不错，还可以。这就是对我的鼓励，所以这时候就非常高兴。但是回头假如她们俩要跟我说，今天晚上我妈妈说了，我们家做好吃的，你来家里吃饭。这个时候我不由自主地心里会很紧张，很紧缩的那种感觉，就知道今天去了准没什么好果子吃。虽然是吃饭去了，但是心里是忐忑不安，甚至是因为吃饭会让我无地自容。高中时在附中的时候我还逃过她的课，这是她极度不能容忍的。所以到她家以后给你好吃的，好菜好饭都放在那。但是她不说你，也不会提醒你，更不会批评你。你以为她会指出你的问题和不足，或者要批评你，但没有，她会直盯盯地看着你，让你自己端着饭碗，吃着好吃的饭菜，让你边吃边痛苦地思考自己，反思自己。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在这种压力之下，你不由自主地会反思和检讨自己。我觉得她对我的教育教导和从心理暗示的走向，给了我积极的正向的一个鼓励和鞭策。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;一块积木的奇遇&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;一块积木的奇遇&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们当时进入附中以后，到了二年级，那时候我还没现在这么胖，喜欢运动，喜欢活动和更多的精力的释放。然后我们几个要好的有相同经历或者相同爱好的同学，就组建了一个相当于是业余的足球队，其实也不叫队，也达不到说是一个足球队的那么多人，就五六个人，组建了一个足球爱好队，用你们现代话说应该叫社团，然后我们当时的口号就是说要踢球，要爱好踢球。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;然后逐渐地我们这个小团队结交了很多校内和校外很多的足球队和很多的朋友。我们虽然踢球一般，但是我们努力，虽然我们技术不好，但是我们那时候心态好，敢于去跟别人较量，敢于去接触别人。有一个词，屡战屡胜，但我们却是屡战屡败，但是我们是在屡战屡败中获得了屡战屡胜的心理认同感。虽然我们赢得少输得多，但是我们收获的却是友情，是对运动的一种尊重和喜爱。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;有一天我们在当时的小球场，也就是现在学校的下沉广场的北边，当时有个场地，我们在那踢小场足球。那天我们和比我们大的一批学长一块比赛，是一场小型的足球比赛。说定的进三个球，哪个队进了三个球以后就先赢，结果那天就闯了祸。我们当时是5个人上场，我司职后卫，结果那天我就有点兴奋过度，后卫解围的时候，本来我们场地小，结果我就使劲使大了，就直接给我们学长一脚踢脸上了。闷脸上以后，我们学长直接就轰然倒地，倒地不醒的样子。当时一看给我们吓坏了，真的是。当时因为都是学生也没经历过这种事，给我们吓坏了。然后大伙就围了上去，围着我们学长说这怎么办？有人就说给它浇点凉水，有的人说给他按人中，然后有的人说不要动他，赶快叫老师叫医生来，或者赶快送到医院去，还有人甚至说赶快给他做人工呼吸。我们正一筹莫展，大伙都在叽叽喳喳的不可开交的时候，我们学长就跟睡醒觉后一样，伸了伸胳膊，捂着脸就醒了过来，醒了以后，突然就说了一句：“刚才是谁闷的我？”哈哈，其实我这一脚还真把我们学长给踢蒙了，他也不知道他自己怎么倒下的。他醒来以后其实是没什么事情，就说短暂的就像眼睛黑了一下，其实没多大的事情，但是当时给我们吓坏了。然后我们等他醒过来又继续踢球，继续玩，然后踢得很淋漓畅快，最后他们是赢了。但是因为这一脚，他们就给我起了一个不好听的外号，叫“老闷”，就是会闷倒人。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我现在偶尔看着孩子们去踢球的时候，我还会回想起当时我在附中时候的这一个小团队，到处跟别人比赛，我们虽然输了，但是从来不会垂头丧气的，我们永远抱有希望，抱有冲劲，自己抱有信心的这么一个状态。到现在我还是这种心理和状态，我感觉特别好。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;一块积木的去向&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;一块积木的去向&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们这个小团队，包括我的所有同学，到最后都走向了不同的学校和不同路线，进入不同的社会岗位。作为当时附中的一名学生来说，当时我们唯一选择就是升学考大学，对吧？所以当时对我们来说，考大学是我们的唯一出路或者理想。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我的考试成绩出来以后，很幸运地进入了清华大学。现在来说好多学生向往清华大学，其实说去清华大学并不是说他就有多高大上，清华大学里也分为很多等级。清华大学最厉害的大伙都知道，建筑系是吧？建筑系，那就相当于清华大学的龙班，清华大学的化学系也不弱，相当于虎班，但是清华大学的艺术系或者是其他文学系的话，用我们的说法叫狗班。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;到了清华大学，其实我当时想的或者说我的追求，是想去清华大学的建筑系，很可惜，能力达不到，心有余力不足，所以只能选择了去其他的系，就不能再接触我最喜欢的建筑理想了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我当时喜欢的就是建筑或者是建筑设计，这是我最喜欢的一个行业，从大学到大学毕业以后，其实我更多的精力和更多的成长都和建筑分不开。你记得上次咱们访谈时候，我跟你说过我一个学长吗？（学长也是北大附中校友，比他大五六届的样子）他后来成为我的领导和同事，他可以说激励我很多年，陪伴我很多年，而且我们一起共事很多年。毕业以后，当时我进入了设计院，建筑设计院。专门从事当时北京地铁的设计工作，当时只有1号线和2号线，然后随着北京规划的越来越大，越来越强的发展以后，北京的地铁发展也越来越快，所以就成立了地铁设计这么一个部门。当时我们在设计院的时候，我承担了一部分地铁线路和地铁的整体规划的一些设计工作，虽然和我当时在大学时候专业不是完全地吻合，但是由于我一直以来的追求和爱好，一直地用心努力，所以我从事这方面的工作也算顺手也不显得突兀，所以我觉得这个选择是正确的，从现在来看当时我的学长，他对我的影响是非常深远的。他是真正的清华大学建筑系毕业的高材生，他又上了研究生，也是上的建筑学科的研究生。所以他属于本土本乡本专业的佼佼者。对我来说，他是我仰慕和羡慕的这么一个学长。最后他学成以后，到了设计院工作，他又是我的领导，给予我的指点，给予我的鼓励，给予我的各种信心，是非常非常多，而且也非常实际，对我的鼓励非常及时。我到现在一直也非常感谢他，也非常尊重他。我觉得他不光是我的学长，而且也是在我一生当中良师和益友这么的关系。所有的同学里面，我对他的印象不仅是学生时期，而且对现在工作来说，是一直非常深刻，非常紧密的一种关系。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;现在这块积木已经成为构筑“社会”这座大厦的一部分，他在最后也有些话想对北大附中现在的学生们说。&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“根据我的经历说几句共勉的话吧。首先说一句，珍惜自己的经历，珍惜自己的爱好，珍惜自己的朋友。这是我现在想对你们这么大的学生说的话。经历、爱好和朋友会陪伴着你的一生，是人生道路上很重要的三个点。你所经历的或者是当时你认为对的事情，你就要认真选择去做。你的经历，你的爱好，你的朋友会逐渐地陪伴和引导你，越来越积极地向上，越来越选择正确的道路，它们会陪伴你走一程，甚至会走一生，能够最后达到从经历转变为经验和社会阅历。你的朋友逐渐会成长为你的良师益友和你的终身陪伴的朋友，这也是很难得的，所以我说的是第一个事情就是你得珍惜这三个重要的要素。第二个，当学生一定要当一个好学生，当一个有好习惯的学生，虽然当时我也调皮，我也闹，但是我希望闹的时候有个度，玩的时候有个够。学的时候有个方向，有个目标，对学生来说尤其重要，尤其对北大附中这么开放的教育，定好自己的目标，把握好自己的学习方向，是非常关键。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“北大附中口述史”人文项目系列文章将陆续在公众号推出，2.0版本实践项目为“北大附中教育口述史”，学生们通过采访老师、校友、学校领导进入附中教育改革史。3.0版本实践项目为“新冠肺炎疫情口述史”，欢迎关注！&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="alumni-stories" /><summary type="html">“我喜欢搭积木，那是我的兴趣。但逐渐地，我的兴趣变成了我的追求，我的梦想。最终，它变成了我的生活，我的工作，我的人生。”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title><link href="/OralHistory/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" /><published>2017-07-27T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front&quot;&gt;There are a few things that you should know up-front:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/pricing&quot;&gt;Ghost(Pro)&lt;/a&gt; service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/&quot;&gt;the Ghost editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>生物</name></author><category term="teacher-picture" /><summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using the Ghost editor</title><link href="/OralHistory/the-editor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using the Ghost editor" /><published>2017-07-27T17:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T17:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/the-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/the-editor">&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses a language called &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; to format text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a &lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Formatting text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common shortcuts are of course, &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; text, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com&quot;&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + B&lt;/code&gt; for Bold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + I&lt;/code&gt; for Italic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; for a Link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + H&lt;/code&gt; for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;insertingimages&quot;&gt;Inserting images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; uploading them to Ghost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;makinglists&quot;&gt;Making lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crack the eggs over a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisk them together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an omellete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed the cat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with idea for next story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;addingquotes&quot;&gt;Adding quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividingthingsup&quot;&gt;Dividing things up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/advanced-markdown/&quot;&gt;Advanced Markdown Guide&lt;/a&gt; - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of &lt;a href=&quot;/using-tags/&quot;&gt;how to use Ghost tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="teacher-picture" /><summary type="html">Ghost uses a language called Markdown to format text. When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause. At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a ? icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts. For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used. Formatting text The most common shortcuts are of course, bold text, italic text, and hyperlinks. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts. CMD/Ctrl + B for Bold CMD/Ctrl + I for Italic CMD/Ctrl + K for a Link CMD/Ctrl + H for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc) With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story. Inserting images Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this: ![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg) Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown. Important Note: Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files before uploading them to Ghost. Making lists Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use * or - or +. Like this: Crack the eggs over a bowl Whisk them together Make an omellete or Remember to buy milk Feed the cat Come up with idea for next story Adding quotes When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &amp;gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients. A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly. Dividing things up If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping --- on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it. This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the Advanced Markdown Guide - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of how to use Ghost tags.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Organising your content with tags</title><link href="/OralHistory/using-tags" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organising your content with tags" /><published>2017-07-27T16:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T16:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/using-tags</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/using-tags">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="teacher-picture" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags. It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content. Basic tagging When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with News and other posts with Cycling, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on /tag/news/ and /tag/cycling/, respectively. If you tag a post with both News and Cycling - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data. The primary tag Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important. News, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports In this example, News is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives. Private tags Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling. For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do. News, Cycling, #video Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News, and Cycling - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting: {{#post}} {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}} ...markup for a nice big video post layout... {{else}} ...regular markup for a post... {{/has}} {{/post}} You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive theme documentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Managing Ghost users</title><link href="/OralHistory/managing-users" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Managing Ghost users" /><published>2017-07-27T15:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T15:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/managing-users</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/managing-users">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are &lt;strong&gt;trusted&lt;/strong&gt; users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;editors&quot;&gt;Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;administrators&quot;&gt;Administrators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;theowner&quot;&gt;The Owner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="teacher-picture" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team Authors The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are trusted users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin. Editors Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site. Administrators The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site. The Owner There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro). It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making your site private</title><link href="/OralHistory/private-sites" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making your site private" /><published>2017-07-27T14:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T14:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/private-sites</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/private-sites">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/private.png&quot; alt=&quot;private&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do remember though, this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="alumni-stories" /><summary type="html">Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase. You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar. Do remember though, this is not secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advanced Markdown tips</title><link href="/OralHistory/advanced-markdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced Markdown tips" /><published>2017-07-27T13:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T13:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/advanced-markdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/advanced-markdown">&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've gotten pretty comfortable with &lt;a href=&quot;/the-editor/&quot;&gt;all the basics&lt;/a&gt; of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you'll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we're using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;strike through&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;mark&gt;highlight&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writingcodeblocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using &lt;a href=&quot;http://prismjs.com/&quot;&gt;Prism.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullbleedimages&quot;&gt;Full bleed images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a &lt;code&gt;#hash&lt;/code&gt; value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/walking.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which is styled with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] {
    max-width: 100vw;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;referencelists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The quick brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fox&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Fox&quot;&gt;fox&lt;/a&gt;, jumped over the lazy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dog&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;creatingfootnotes&quot;&gt;Creating footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quick brown fox&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; jumped over the lazy dog&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullhtml&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foxes are red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dogs are usually not red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="teacher-picture" /><summary type="html">There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor If you've gotten pretty comfortable with all the basics of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown! As with the last post about the editor, you'll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we're using. Special formatting As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example: strike through highlight *escaped characters* Writing code blocks There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, like this. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks: .my-link { text-decoration: underline; } If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Prism.js. Full bleed images One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a #hash value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example: which is styled with... img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] { max-width: 100vw; } This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles. Reference lists The quick brown fox, jumped over the lazy dog. Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference. Creating footnotes The quick brown fox[1] jumped over the lazy dog[2]. Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post. Full HTML Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example: Foxes are red ↩︎ Dogs are usually not red ↩︎</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting up your own Ghost theme</title><link href="/OralHistory/themes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting up your own Ghost theme" /><published>2017-07-27T12:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T12:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/themes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/themes">&lt;p&gt;Creating a totally custom design for your publication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost comes with a beautiful default theme called Casper, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for most purposes. However, Ghost can also be completely themed to suit your needs. Rather than just giving you a few basic settings which act as a poor proxy for code, we just let you write code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a huge range of both free and premium pre-built themes which you can get from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketplace.ghost.org&quot;&gt;Ghost Theme Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, or you can simply create your own from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://marketplace.ghost.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/marketplace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;marketplace&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can write a completely custom Ghost theme, with just some solid knowledge of HTML and CSS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost themes are written with a templating language called handlebars, which has a bunch of dynamic helpers to insert your data into template files. Like &lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, for example, outputs the name of the current author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn how to write your own Ghost theme is to have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TryGhost/Casper&quot;&gt;the source code for Casper&lt;/a&gt;, which is heavily commented and should give you a sense of how everything fits together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;default.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the main template file, all contexts will load inside this file unless specifically told to use a different template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;post.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the file used in the context of viewing a post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;index.hbs&lt;/code&gt; is the file used in the context of viewing the home page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've got &lt;a href=&quot;http://themes.ghost.org/docs/about&quot;&gt;full and extensive theme documentation&lt;/a&gt; which outlines every template file, context and helper that you can use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to chat with other people making Ghost themes to get any advice or help, there's also a &lt;strong&gt;#themes&lt;/strong&gt; channel in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.ghost.org&quot;&gt;public Slack community&lt;/a&gt; which we always recommend joining!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="teacher-picture" /><summary type="html">Creating a totally custom design for your publication Ghost comes with a beautiful default theme called Casper, which is designed to be a clean, readable publication layout and can be easily adapted for most purposes. However, Ghost can also be completely themed to suit your needs. Rather than just giving you a few basic settings which act as a poor proxy for code, we just let you write code. There are a huge range of both free and premium pre-built themes which you can get from the Ghost Theme Marketplace, or you can simply create your own from scratch. Anyone can write a completely custom Ghost theme, with just some solid knowledge of HTML and CSS Ghost themes are written with a templating language called handlebars, which has a bunch of dynamic helpers to insert your data into template files. Like , for example, outputs the name of the current author. The best way to learn how to write your own Ghost theme is to have a look at the source code for Casper, which is heavily commented and should give you a sense of how everything fits together. default.hbs is the main template file, all contexts will load inside this file unless specifically told to use a different template. post.hbs is the file used in the context of viewing a post. index.hbs is the file used in the context of viewing the home page. and so on We've got full and extensive theme documentation which outlines every template file, context and helper that you can use. If you want to chat with other people making Ghost themes to get any advice or help, there's also a #themes channel in our public Slack community which we always recommend joining!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Businessman &amp;amp; The Fisherman</title><link href="/OralHistory/the-businessman-and-fisherman" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Businessman &amp; The Fisherman" /><published>2014-08-12T18:18:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-08-12T18:18:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/the-businessman-and-fisherman</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/the-businessman-and-fisherman">&lt;p&gt;An American businessman took a vacation to a small coastal Mexican village on doctor’s orders. Unable to sleep after an urgent phone call from the office the first morning, he walked out to the pier to clear his head. A small boat with just one fisherman had docked, and inside the boat were several large yellowfin tuna. The American complimented the Mexican on the quality of his fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How long did it take you to catch them?” the American asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Only a little while,” the Mexican replied in surprisingly good English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why don’t you stay out longer and catch more fish?” the American then asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have enough to support my family and give a few to friends,” the Mexican said as he unloaded them into a basket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But… What do you do with the rest of your time?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mexican looked up and smiled. “I sleep late, fish a little, play with my children, take a siesta with my wife, Julia, and stroll into the village each evening, where I sip wine and play guitar with my amigos. I have a full and busy life, señor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The American laughed and stood tall. “Sir, I’m a Harvard M.B.A. and can help you. You should spend more time fishing, and with the proceeds, buy a bigger boat. In no time, you could buy several boats with the increased haul. Eventually, you would have a fleet of fishing boats.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He continued, “Instead of selling your catch to a middleman, you would sell directly to the consumers, eventually opening your own cannery. You would control the product, processing, and distribution. You would need to leave this small coastal fishing village, of course, and move to Mexico City, then to Los Angeles, and eventually to New York City, where you could run your expanded enterprise with proper management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mexican fisherman asked, “But, señor, how long will all this take?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To which the American replied, “15-20 years, 25 tops.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But what then, señor?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The American laughed and said, “That’s the best part. When the time is right, you would announce an IPO and sell your company stock to the public and become very rich. You would make millions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Millions señor? Then what?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then you would retire and move to a small coastal fishing village, where you would sleep late, fish a little, play with your kids, take a siesta with your wife, and stroll in to the village in the evenings where you could sip wine and play your guitar with your amigos.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adapted from the “Anekdote zur Senkung der Arbeitsmoral” by &lt;strong&gt;Heinrich Böll&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An influential German write and Nobel Prize for Literature in 1972.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Wolfe</name></author><category term="fables" /><summary type="html">An American businessman took a vacation to a small coastal Mexican village on doctor’s orders. Unable to sleep after an urgent phone call from the office the first morning, he walked out to the pier to clear his head. A small boat with just one fisherman had docked, and inside the boat were several large yellowfin tuna. The American complimented the Mexican on the quality of his fish.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Full and Comprehensive Style Test</title><link href="/OralHistory/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Full and Comprehensive Style Test" /><published>2012-09-01T18:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2012-09-01T18:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/OralHistory/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OralHistory/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test">&lt;p&gt;Below is just about everything you’ll need to style in the theme. Check the source code to see the many embedded elements within paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;heading1&quot;&gt;Heading 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading2&quot;&gt;Heading 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heading3&quot;&gt;Heading 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;heading4&quot;&gt;Heading 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heading5&quot;&gt;Heading 5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading6&quot;&gt;Heading 6&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, &lt;a title=&quot;test link&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;test link&lt;/a&gt; adipiscing elit. &lt;strong&gt;This is strong.&lt;/strong&gt; Nullam dignissim convallis est. Quisque aliquam. &lt;em&gt;This is emphasized.&lt;/em&gt; Donec faucibus. Nunc iaculis suscipit dui. 5&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; = 125. Water is H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O. Nam sit amet sem. Aliquam libero nisi, imperdiet at, tincidunt nec, gravida vehicula, nisl. &lt;cite&gt;The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt; (That’s a citation). &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration:underline;&quot;&gt;Underline.&lt;/span&gt; Maecenas ornare tortor. Donec sed tellus eget sapien fringilla nonummy. Mauris a ante. Suspendisse quam sem, consequat at, commodo vitae, feugiat in, nunc. Morbi imperdiet augue quis tellus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Hyper Text Markup Language&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/abbr&gt; and &lt;abbr title=&quot;Cascading Style Sheets&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/abbr&gt; are our tools. Mauris a ante. Suspendisse quam sem, consequat at, commodo vitae, feugiat in, nunc. Morbi imperdiet augue quis tellus.  Praesent mattis, massa quis luctus fermentum, turpis mi volutpat justo, eu volutpat enim diam eget metus. To copy a file type &lt;code&gt;COPY &lt;var&gt;filename&lt;/var&gt;&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;del&gt;Dinner’s at 5:00.&lt;/del&gt; &lt;ins&gt;Let’s make that 7.&lt;/ins&gt; This &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration:line-through;&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; has been struck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;media&quot;&gt;Media&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bigimage&quot;&gt;Big Image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://demo.ghost.io/content/images/2014/09/testimg1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Test Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;smallimage&quot;&gt;Small Image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://demo.ghost.io/content/images/2014/09/testimg2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small Test Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labore et dolore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;listtypes&quot;&gt;List Types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;definitionlist&quot;&gt;Definition List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Definition List Title&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;This is a definition list division.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Definition&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;An exact statement or description of the nature, scope, or meaning of something: &lt;em&gt;our definition of what constitutes poetry.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;orderedlist&quot;&gt;Ordered List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item 1  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item 2 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nested list item A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nested list item B&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unorderedlist&quot;&gt;Unordered List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item 2
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nested list item A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nested list item B&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;table&quot;&gt;Table&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Table Header 1&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Table Header 2&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Table Header 3&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Division 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preformattedtext&quot;&gt;Preformatted Text&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typographically, preformatted text is not the same thing as code. Sometimes, a faithful execution of the text requires preformatted text that may not have anything to do with code. Most browsers use Courier and that’s a good default — with one slight adjustment, Courier 10 Pitch over regular Courier for Linux users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code can be presented inline, like &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?php bloginfo('stylesheet_url'); ?&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, or within a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; block. Because we have more specific typographic needs for code, we’ll specify Consolas and Monaco ahead of the browser-defined monospace font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code blocks can also be inserted with the highlight tag as below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
    
    {% highlight language-x %}
    # some code
    {% endhighlight %}
    
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information about code highlighting in jekyll can be found  &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/templates/#code-snippet-highlighting&quot;&gt;in Jekyll documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These area a couple of examples showing the resulting highlighted code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* css code sample */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#container&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;margin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;-240px&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// javascript code sample&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ajax&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'POST'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'backend.php'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;q=&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;myform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;serialize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;success&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// on success use return data here&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;xhr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;exception&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// if ajax fails display error alert&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;alert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;ajax error response type &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can also use &lt;a href=&quot;https://highlightjs.org/&quot;&gt;highlight.js&lt;/a&gt;.
For more on how to use it and on the available styles check their
&lt;a href=&quot;https://highlightjs.org/static/demo/&quot;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://highlightjs.readthedocs.org/en/latest/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;system&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;swift&quot;&gt;// Swift code sample
import Foundation

@objc class Person: Entity {
  var name: String!
  var age:  Int!

  init(name: String, age: Int) {
    /* /* ... */ */
  }

  // Return a descriptive string for this person
  func description(offset: Int = 0) -&gt; String {
    return &quot;\(name) is \(age + offset) years old&quot;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockquotes&quot;&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s keep it simple. Italics are good to help set it off from the body text. Be sure to style the citation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Good afternoon, gentlemen. I am a HAL 9000 computer. I became operational at the H.A.L. plant in Urbana, Illinois on the 12th of January 1992. My instructor was Mr. Langley, and he taught me to sing a song. If you’d like to hear it I can sing it for you. &lt;cite&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HAL_9000&quot;&gt;HAL 9000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s a bit of trailing text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;textlevelsemantics&quot;&gt;Text-level semantics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;a element&lt;/a&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;abbr&gt;abbr element&lt;/abbr&gt; and &lt;abbr title=&quot;Title text&quot;&gt;abbr element with title&lt;/abbr&gt; examples &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;b&gt;b element&lt;/b&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;cite&gt;cite element&lt;/cite&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;code element&lt;/code&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;del&gt;del element&lt;/del&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;dfn&gt;dfn element&lt;/dfn&gt; and &lt;dfn title=&quot;Title text&quot;&gt;dfn element with title&lt;/dfn&gt; examples &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;em&gt;em element&lt;/em&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;i element&lt;/i&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;ins&gt;ins element&lt;/ins&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;kbd&gt;kbd element&lt;/kbd&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;mark&gt;mark element&lt;/mark&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;q&gt;q element &lt;q&gt;inside&lt;/q&gt; a q element&lt;/q&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;s&gt;s element&lt;/s&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;samp&gt;samp element&lt;/samp&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;small&gt;small element&lt;/small&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;span&gt;span element&lt;/span&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;strong element&lt;/strong&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;sub&gt;sub element&lt;/sub&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;sup&gt;sup element&lt;/sup&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;var&gt;var element&lt;/var&gt; example &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;u&gt;u element&lt;/u&gt; example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forms&quot;&gt;Forms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;form&gt;
&lt;fieldset&gt;
&lt;legend&gt;Inputs as descendents of labels (form legend)&lt;/legend&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Text input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; value=&quot;default value&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Email input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;email&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Search input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;search&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Tel input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;tel&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;URL input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;url&quot; placeholder=&quot;http://&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Password input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;password&quot; value=&quot;password&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;File input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;file&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Radio input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;radio&quot; name=&quot;rad&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Checkbox input&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;radio&quot; name=&quot;rad&quot;&gt; Radio input
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt; Checkbox input
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Select field&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;select&gt;
&lt;option&gt;Option 01&lt;/option&gt;
&lt;option&gt;Option 02&lt;/option&gt;
&lt;/select&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;label&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Textarea&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;textarea cols=&quot;30&quot; rows=&quot;5&quot; &gt;Textarea text&lt;/textarea&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/fieldset&gt;

&lt;fieldset&gt;
&lt;legend&gt;Clickable inputs and buttons&lt;/legend&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://placekitten.com/90/24&quot; alt=&quot;Image (input)&quot;&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;reset&quot; value=&quot;Reset (input)&quot;&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;button&quot; value=&quot;Button (input)&quot;&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Submit (input)&quot;&gt;
&lt;button type=&quot;reset&quot;&gt;Reset (button)&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Button (button)&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;button type=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;Submit (button)&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/fieldset&gt;

&lt;fieldset id=&quot;boxsize&quot;&gt;
&lt;legend&gt;box-sizing tests&lt;/legend&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; value=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; value=&quot;email&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;search&quot; value=&quot;search&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;url&quot; value=&quot;http://example.com&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;password&quot; value=&quot;password&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;color&quot; value=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;number&quot; value=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;range&quot; value=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;date&quot; value=&quot;1970-01-01&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;month&quot; value=&quot;1970-01&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;week&quot; value=&quot;1970-W01&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;time&quot; value=&quot;18:23&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;datetime&quot; value=&quot;1970-01-01T00:00:00Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;datetime-local&quot; value=&quot;1970-01-01T00:00&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;radio&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;select&gt;&lt;option&gt;Option 01&lt;/option&gt;&lt;option&gt;Option 02&lt;/option&gt;&lt;/select&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;textarea cols=&quot;30&quot; rows=&quot;5&quot; &gt;Textarea text&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://placekitten.com/90/24&quot; alt=&quot;Image (input)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;reset&quot; value=&quot;Reset (input)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;button&quot; value=&quot;Button (input)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Submit (input)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;reset&quot;&gt;Reset (button)&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Button (button)&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;button type=&quot;submit&quot;&gt;Submit (button)&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/fieldset&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;embeds&quot;&gt;Embeds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes all you want to do is embed a little love from another location and set your post alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/103224792?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slides&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async class=&quot;speakerdeck-embed&quot; data-id=&quot;34d2856027ce01316b5d621ab8e7d421&quot; data-ratio=&quot;1.33333333333333&quot; src=&quot;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;audio&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/169381837&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;bcqhe&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;js&quot; data-user=&quot;rglazebrook&quot; class='codepen'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var c = new Sketch.create({autoclear: false}),
    bigCircle = 50,
    littleCircle = 5,
    // The velocity value determines how much to move the spinner head (in radians).
    velocity = 0.105,
    hue = 0,
    // The alpha value below determines the length of the spinner&amp;#39;s tail.
    bg = &amp;#39;rgba(40,40,40,.075)&amp;#39;;
    Spinner = function() {};

Spinner.prototype.setup = function() {
  this.x = c.width / 2;
  this.y = c.height / 2 - bigCircle;
  this.rotation = 0;
}
Spinner.prototype.update = function() {
  this.rotation += velocity;
  this.rotation = this.rotation % TWO_PI;
  this.x = c.width /2 + cos(this.rotation) * bigCircle;
  this.y = c.height / 2 + sin(this.rotation) * bigCircle;
}
Spinner.prototype.draw = function() {
  c.fillStyle = &amp;#39;hsl(&amp;#39;+hue+&amp;#39;,50%,50%)&amp;#39;;
  c.beginPath();
  c.arc(this.x, this.y, littleCircle, 0, TWO_PI);
  c.fill();
  c.closePath();
}
c.setup = function() {
  spinner = new Spinner();
  spinner.setup();
}
c.update = function() {
  spinner.update();
  hue = ++hue % 360;
}
c.draw = function() {
  spinner.draw();
  c.fillStyle = bg;
  c.fillRect(0,0,c.width,c.height);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/rglazebrook/pen/bcqhe/'&gt;Simple Rotating Spinner&lt;/a&gt; by Rob Glazebrook (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/rglazebrook'&gt;@rglazebrook&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn't it beautiful?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>John O'Nolan</name></author><summary type="html">Below is just about everything you’ll need to style in the theme. Check the source code to see the many embedded elements within paragraphs.</summary></entry></feed>